<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<s:scufl xmlns:s="http://org.embl.ebi.escience/xscufl/0.1alpha" version="0.2" log="0">
  <s:workflowdescription lsid="urn:lsid:net.sf.taverna:wfDefinition:2c41ee6e-a8c0-42e2-a09f-9be44bc11b98" author="Allyson Lister, a.l.lister@newcastle.ac.uk" title="GetSymbaLsidData">More information is available from http://symba.sf.net

This webservice is not directly used within SyMBA, but is instead available as part of ongoing work to have the SyMBA LSID webservices conform to the LSID specification (http://lsids.sourceforge.net/quick-links/lsid-spec/). It can also be used by people wishing to access the SyMBA database directly, via programmatic means, rather than via the web interface.

This workflow's purpose is to retrieve the FuGE-ML-structured metadata from SyMBA that is associated with the given LSID. Currently it only works for LSIDs associated with FuGE elements or ExternalData elements, though this will be extended shortly.

However, it is agnostic to the type of use, and can be built from SyMBA Subversion to have a different set of requirements and return types, so that you can customize it for your own purposes. 

SyMBA does much more than just provide some LSID services: it's a FuGE database, web interface, and API for loading and sharing FuGE-structured data and metadata for the life sciences. Contact us at symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net or stop by the website for more information.</s:workflowdescription>
  <s:processor name="getData">
    <s:arbitrarywsdl>
      <s:wsdl>http://bsu.ncl.ac.uk:8081/symba-lsid-ws-resolver/services/LsidDataRetriever?wsdl</s:wsdl>
      <s:operation>getData</s:operation>
    </s:arbitrarywsdl>
  </s:processor>
  <s:processor name="parametersXML">
    <s:local>
      org.embl.ebi.escience.scuflworkers.java.XMLInputSplitter
      <s:extensions>
        <s:complextype optional="false" unbounded="false" typename="getData" name="parameters" qname="{http://service.webservices.lsid.symba.sourceforge.net/}getData">
          <s:elements>
            <s:basetype optional="true" unbounded="false" typename="string" name="lsid" qname="getData&gt;lsid" />
          </s:elements>
        </s:complextype>
      </s:extensions>
    </s:local>
  </s:processor>
  <s:link source="lsid" sink="parametersXML:lsid" />
  <s:link source="parametersXML:output" sink="getData:parameters" />
  <s:source name="lsid">
    <s:metadata>
      <s:mimeTypes>
        <s:mimeType>text/xml</s:mimeType>
      </s:mimeTypes>
    </s:metadata>
  </s:source>
  <s:sink name="LsidDataValue">
    <s:metadata>
      <s:description>While this generally will return FuGE-ML-structured metadata, if you call this method on a RawData-namespaced LSID, it will return the raw data itself, upon which all of the FuGE metadata is based.</s:description>
    </s:metadata>
  </s:sink>
</s:scufl>

