<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>SyMBA</title>
        <author email="allysonlister.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Allyson Lister</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <!--<release version="current" description="Current work version">-->
        <!--<action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add|fix|remove|update">-->
        <!--A new cool feature.-->
        <!--</action>-->
        <!--</release>-->
        <release version="8.08" date="soon"
                 description="Upgrade to FuGE Version 1">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                We now allow material transformation protocols as well as data creation (Assay) protocols. See the
                MiMage-*.xml documents (part of the symba-mapping module) in the Subversion repository.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                We have upgraded SyMBA to FuGE Version 1. Up until this release, SyMBA has been using FuGE Milestone 3.
                At the same time, we have refactored a lot of code, and cleaned up as we went. Now that there is both
                an official FuGE XSD STK and an official FuGE Hibernate STK, SyMBA starts with these toolkits and builds
                from them.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="8.05" date="2008-05-09"
                 description="Bug Fixes, Improvements to Protocol Template and Search Functionality">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Up until now, as soon as the files were uploaded, they were put into byte arrays and kept in the session
                memory until final submission of the information. While correct, it would quickly become inefficient
                when large numbers of large files are being loaded. Now it just keeps the File object in the session,
                and only reads in that file upon commit of the form. To Do: check (during rawData.jsp) that the file
                is OK.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Made an interface from which different types of copying of the data files (srb, scp, etc) can be used.
                This can be found by examining the net.sourceforge.symba.webapp.util.storage classes in the webapp-helper
                sub-project.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Factored out the beans from the webapp directory and made them their own sub-project, so they can be
                referred to by other sub-projects on their own, as a jar, without being bundled directly in the war.
                Their new location is the webapp-helper directory.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Improved session management when loading the data, as well as the ability to copy metadata from one
                data file into the form for loading another data file, to save time and effort.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                SyMBA now integrates (optionally) with a security server. In earlier snapshot releases,
                the jars needed to connect to this server were built within the SyMBA web/ subproject. However,
                this jar is now part of the maven2 manual install in the lib/ directory. This means that users who do
                not plan to use the security server are not required to build it.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                The search results screen now orders the returned experiments by date of creation, and also shows
                the date created after the name of the experiment.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1921120">
                Added a direct link to downloading the PostgreSQL jar.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1921046">
                The opening &lt;settings&gt; element in the installation instructions (for the maven settings.xml file)
                was missing, so if people copied it in its entirety, it wouldn't validate. This has been fixed.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix">
                There was a bug that meant that the description of a file wasn't being entered into the final
                FuGE entry. This has now been fixed.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="delete">
                The now-obsolete CannedSearch class has been removed.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Once the data file is loaded, the original filename is displayed in the successive forms to help
                users remember which data file's metadata they're entering.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                SyMBA now has a public project management website! Visit http://mygrid.ncl.ac.uk/symba
                (username and pwd: symba-public). If you wish to contribute to the tasks, or even take a task yourself
                please email one of the developers (click on our names on this page) to ask for a login specific
                to you.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="update">
                The retrieval of the existing experiment selection (the first step in adding a new data file to an
                already-extant experiment) now uses a much faster database query.
            </action>
            <action dev="Frank Gibson, Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Additions to the CSS have been made that allow each group of form fields to be visually grouped
                into separate boxes.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1881897">
                There was a problem where one of the ontology terms was getting displayed as its LSID rather than
                as its proper name in confirm.jsp. This has now been fixed.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="update" issue="1934585">
                There really isn't a suitable type for this change. It is a resolved tracker issue, but it is not
                one where changes needed to be applied. Both the fieldset's label being half-in and half-out
                of the fieldset, and the lack of an ability to resize these fieldsets are normal behaviour for
                the operating systems and web browsers specified.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="update" issue="1934581">
                Please see change directly above.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1854867">
                The underscore in the CHARACTER_VARYING of the SQL to use to create the "users" table in the
                Installation Guide is unnecessary and confusing. This has been removed in the xdocs (install.xml).
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1918032">
                There was a request to make "Type, Dose and Length of Treatment:" truly optional by removing it from the
                code and placing in the XML, possibly as a treatment protocol.
                There are two solutions: 1) create a treament protocol, tie it to your main protocol, and then put in
                the relevant GenericParameters for the treatments you're interested in, or 2) make the treatment work
                as a description on the GenericMaterial, and simply ensure that this (treatment) part of the form
                will no longer appear if the Material Dummy's name attribute (in the Protocol Template) contains
                the exact set of chars: " Notreatment" somewhere in the string. This should come after the " Dummy"
                statement in that string. The latter is the solution applied to SyMBA, though the former might be
                a more elegant way of solving the problem, and may be possible in the future. While the former idea
                (using a treatment protocol) is a good one, at the moment SyMBA is set up around the concept of the data
                file. This means that, currently, SyMBA users cannot add information to a protocol when they are not
                also adding a data file.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1918030">
                There was a request to remove the hard-coded "Name/ID of this Material (optional):" option and move
                it to a describable element in the XML. This has been accomplished in that this part of the form
                will no longer appear if the Material Dummy's name attribute (in the Protocol Template) contains
                the exact set of chars: " Noname" somewhere in the string. This should come after the " Dummy" statement
                in that string.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="8.03" date="2008-03-13"
                 description="Improvements to Protocol Template Functionality and Search Functionality">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                May now view all experiments in the database (i.e. not just your own).
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1881894">
                Now have the ability to search based on any ontology term in the database.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                EquipmentApplications have now been added.
            </action>
            <action dev="Frank Gibson" type="update">
                The CARMEN neuroscience project's reference template has been massively extended.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="8.01" date="2008-01-29" description="Improvements to Protocol Template Functionality">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister, Frank Gibson" type="update">
                The CARMEN neuroscience project required a modification to the way the Protocol Templates are
                handled by the SyMBA webapp. All code changes for this release reflect this need.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="7.11" date="2007-11-23" description="Update from Andromda 3.2-SNAPSHOT to Andromda 3.2">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="update">
                As the latest Andromda snapshot is now 3.3-SNAPSHOT, it is no longer appropriate to be using
                3.2-SNAPSHOT. Therefore, we have upgraded the Andromda plugin to version 3.2.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="7.10" date="2007-10-05" description="Bug Fixes, Installation Instruction Improvements">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1799676">
                SyMBA Bug Tracker post: "SyMBA help navigation button returns front page only". Fixed by removing the
                requirement to log on to view the help pages.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1799673">
                SyMBA Bug Tracker post: "[why?] box on login page does not answer question". Fix for issue 1799676 also
                resolved this bug.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1799665">
                SyMBA Bug Tracker post: "Link for 'SyMBA project Home Page' is incorrect". Erroneous URL fixed in
                menu-static.html.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1807553">
                SyMBA Bug Tracker post: "bug with Sample Microarray in sandbox". Error in the LoadFuge class
                caused erroneous loading, and therefore viewing, of the sample microarray protocols. Now fixed.
            </action>
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add" issue="1807551">
                SyMBA Feature Tracker post: "ability to turn on/off debug statments". This feature was added for both
                RealizableEntityServiceImpl and CisbanHelper
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="7.09" date="2007-09-17" description="Upgrade to Maven 2, Promotion to SourceForge">
            <action dev="Allyson Lister" type="add">
                Upgraded from Maven1 to Maven2.
            </action>
            <!--<action dev="Allyson Lister" type="fix" issue="1254">-->
            <!--<action dev="Allyson Lister" type="delete">-->
            <!--Removed a feature that nobody liked.-->
            <!--</action>-->
        </release>
    </body>
</document>
