<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <author email="allysonlister.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Allyson Lister</author>
        <author email="ollyshaw.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Olly Shaw</author>
        <title>SyMBA Technical Documentation</title>
    </properties>
    <meta name="keyword"
          content="SyMBA, Systems Biology, Data Archive, CISBAN, FuGE, Computational Biology, Ageing, Aging, Nutrition, Kirkwood, Biological Modelling, Biological Modeling"/>
    <body>
        <section name="Current Release: 7.09 (stable)">

            <p>
                This page describes technical details of SyMBA. For more
                general information please see the
                <a href="index.html">home page</a>
                .
            </p>

            <p>
                <font color="red">There is currently a problem with the server running the SyMBA sandbox. It should be
                    back up and running
                    sometime next week. We apologize for any inconvenience.
                </font>
            </p>

            <p>
                We are pleased to announce that SyMBA is pretty stable and available in a
                public sandbox version.
                Please note that the configuration at this url, while representing the first stable release, remains a
                sandbox
                configuration, and any data you may upload to the server may be deleted at any time. We will, however,
                try to send
                out warning emails prior to any deletion of the database. As a sandbox implementation, it should not be
                used as a
                permanent archive for any data. If you wish to have an archive to store your high-throughput data,
                please
                <a href="mailto:symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net">contact us</a>
                to see if we could collaborate in any way.
            </p>
        </section>

        <section name="References">

            <p>
                You may find the following useful:
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <a href="http://www.cs.ncl.ac.uk/research/pubs/trs/abstract.php?number=1016">CS-TR:
                        1016 Implementing the FuGE Object Model: a Systems Biology Data Portal and Integrator
                    </a>
                    ,
                    <i>Lister, A. L., Jones, A. R., Pocock, M., Shaw, O., Wipat, A.</i>
                    School of Computing Science, Newcastle University, Apr 2007.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Jones AR, Pizarro A, Spellman P, Miller M; FuGE Working Group.
                    <a href="http://www.liebertonline.com/doi/abs/10.1089/omi.2006.10.179">FuGE: Functional Genomics
                        Experiment
                        Object Model
                    </a>
                    , OMICS: A Journal of Integrative Biology, 2006 10:2 p179-184.
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>

        <section name="Using the Sandbox">
            <subsection name="Logging In">

                <p>
                    You will need a logon to access this database, which you may request
                    from the
                    <a href="mailto:symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net">helpdesk</a>
                    . This is a low-level of security that will
                    only serve to prevent anonymous load on the database and to keep your sandbox area separate from
                    others.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="What we mean by a 'sandbox' release">

                <p>
                    We reserve the right to stop and restart the DPI server at any time, and to drop and re-create the
                    database
                    at any time. You should not attempt to use this service as a long-term, permanent store.
                    However, we encourage you to upload data and create as many experiments as you like
                    so that you may determine if this application may be of use to your own research group. We also
                    appreciate
                    you
                    <a href="mailto:symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net">contacting us</a>
                    with any comments or questions you may have.
                </p>

                <p>
                    Further, although we do have an LSID Resolution Service running via
                    <a href="http://elephant.ncl.ac.uk:8081/authority">http://elephant.ncl.ac.uk:8081/authority</a>
                    , and we
                    do aim to ensure that object returned will always return the same thing, not every object identified
                    with
                    an LSID can currently be resolved via this service. This is still within the standard: if something
                    resolves,
                    it must always be to the same thing. However, you are free to test the LSID server now. More
                    information on
                    contacting the LSID Resolution Service will be added shortly, together with an example Java class.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Standards Used">

            <p>
                Our back-end, and the XML produced by the front-end, is completely
                <a href="http://fuge.sourceforge.net">FuGE-compliant</a>
                .
                CISBAN is part of the
                <a href="http://www.mged.org/Workgroups/rsbi/rsbi.html">RSBI Consortium</a>
                , which
                encourages the use of three main reporting standards
                for biological investigations:
                <a href="http://fuge.sourceforge.net">FuGE</a>
                ,
                <a href="http://obi.sourceforge.net">OBI</a>
                , and
                <a href="http://mibbi.sourceforge.net">MIBBI</a>
                . FuGE is
                a maturing standard data model for storing experimental metadata, OBI is a developing standard ontology
                for
                biological/biomedical experiments, and MIBBI is a new effort to standardize the minimum information
                needed
                to describe a biological experiment.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="What does the release number mean?">

            <p>
                We have based the release numbering system on the
                <a href="http://www.ubuntu.com">Ubuntu</a>
                style. This
                means that the number prefixing the "." is the year of the release, and the number after the "." is the
                month of the release. Therefore, release 7.03 was released in March 2007. Finally, we add a comment
                after
                the release number detailing whether the release is a beta version or a stable version.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Does this project suit your needs?">

            <p>
                We are interested in collaboration with any group that may be able to make use of this project. Most
                aspects
                of the application are generic, and the main way of customizing the DPI is via creation and upload of
                your
                own experimental protocols.

            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="What are we planning in future?">
            <ul>
                <li>A Protocol Wizard for adding protocols via the gui rather than the command line</li>
                <li>An ontology term tracker that could automatically add terms to the interface, as this is the main
                    way
                    the experimental factors are stored.
                </li>
                <li>Upgrade of the system to FuGE Version 1 (and therefore UML 2), once it has been finalized.</li>
                <li>Upgrade of the build system to Maven 2 (
                    <font color="red">completed</font>
                    )
                    and AndroMDA 4.
                </li>
                <li>Download of the entire system so that others may install it for their own use.</li>
                <li>An Administration page that allows a view of the entire contents of the database (those that aren't
                    marked
                    as private) from the front-end.
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>