<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <author email="allysonlister.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Allyson Lister</author>
        <author email="ollyshaw.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Olly Shaw</author>
        <title>Past SyMBA/CISBAN DPI Status Reports</title>
    </properties>
    <meta name="keyword"
          content="SyMBA, Systems Biology, Data Archive, CISBAN, FuGE, Computational Biology, Metadata"/>
    <body>

        <section name="Past SyMBA/CISBAN DPI Status Reports">

            <p>
                Status reports that are no longer current may be found here.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Status: May 2008: 8.05">
                <p>
                    A large number of changes were incorporated into this release, mainly dealing with
                    session management, bug fixing, and code refactoring. For more information, please
                    see the<a href="changes-report.html">Change Report</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Status: March 2008: 8.03">

                <p>
                    A number of new searches have been added, and we have extended the options available to users
                    building SyMBA templates (see the<a href="changes-report.html">Change Report</a>).
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: January 2008: 8.01">

                <p>
                    The CARMEN neuroscience project required a modification to the way the Protocol Templates are
                    handled by the SyMBA webapp. All code changes for this release reflect this need.
                    (see the<a href="changes-report.html">Change Report</a>).
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Status: November 2007: 7.11">

                <p>
                    The main feature of this release is the upgrading of the Andromda plugin from 3.2-SNAPSHOT to 3.2
                    (see the<a href="changes-report.html">Change Report</a>).
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Status: October 2007: 7.10">

                <p>
                    This is an incremental release that was mainly created to fix a few minor bugs and added a feature
                    (see the<a href="changes-report.html">Change Report</a>). The entire SyMBA project now runs wholly
                    from
                    SourceForge.
                </p>

            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Status: September 2007: Second Stable Release (7.09 stable)">

                <p>
                    This is an incremental release that was mainly created to fix a few minor bugs, and to bring the
                    code
                    up to a standard that could be deposited into the SourceForge Subversion repository. It is built
                    with
                    Maven 2.0.7, an improvement on the earlier maven 1 build system.
                    At the same time as the sandbox release of 7.09 is published, the full code of SyMBA will be
                    deposited
                    on SourceForge.
                </p>

            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: June 2007: First Stable Release (7.06 stable)">

                <p>
                    The following changes have been made to SyMBA since 7.04:
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <em>Removal of the RawData and associated classes.</em>
                            As the location where the
                            permanent database was to reside would not have the space required to store the
                            high-throughput data, and
                            because we wanted to decouple data storage from metadata storage, we now
                            use a file store for the data. The database stores only experimental FuGE-standard metadata.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <em>More complex Protocol display handling.</em>
                            Much more complicated Protocols can now
                            be handled by the front-end. While the FuGE database back-end has always been able to handle
                            the full range
                            of FuGE metadata, the front-end has been kept deliberately simple. However, work is
                            progressing to enable
                            the front-end to display more complex protocols when needed. This is the first step in the
                            creation of
                            a "Protocol Generation Wizard", which will be a method to create new Protocols for the
                            database on the fly,
                            via the front-end. Currently the only way to add new Protocols to the database is via XML
                            upload directly to
                            the database.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: April 2007: Second Beta Release (7.04 beta)">

                <p>
                    The CISBAN Data Portal and Integrator is now available in a beta-stage
                    <a href="http://bsu.ncl.ac.uk:8081/portal">public sandbox version</a>
                    .
                    Please note that this is not yet a stable release, and any data you may upload to the
                    server may be deleted at any time. Major changes since last month include multiple-file upload
                    facilities,
                    and a more generic system for reading and displaying the protocols from the database.
                    You will need a logon to access this database, which you may request
                    from the
                    <a href="mailto:symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net">symba-devel</a>
                    mailing list
                    . This is low-level security that
                    only serves to prevent anonymous load on the database and to keep your sandbox area separate from
                    others.
                    For more information on the sandbox SyMBA, please visit SyMBA's
                    <a href="details.html">technical documentation</a>
                    .
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: March 2007: First Beta Release">

                <p>
                    We are pleased to announce that the CISBAN Data Portal and Integrator is now available in a
                    <a href="http://bsu.ncl.ac.uk:8081/portal">public sandbox version</a>
                    .
                    Please note that this release is still at an early beta stage, and any data you may upload to the
                    server may be deleted at any time. You will need a logon to access this database, which you may
                    request
                    from the
                    <a href="mailto:symba-devel@lists.sourceforge.net">symba-devel</a>
                    mailing list
                    . This is a low-level of security that will
                    only serve to prevent anonymous load on the database and to keep your sandbox area separate from
                    others.
                    For more information on the sandbox SyMBA, please visit SyMBA's
                    <a href="details.html">technical documentation</a>
                    .
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: February 2007">

                <p>
                    We are on-track to get a sandbox version of SyMBA out by the first week of March, and an initial
                    download a
                    week or two after that. I've now extended the UML further to include more queries over the database,
                    and I've
                    added a "friendly" identifier to the RawData class. This friendly ID is unique but optional, and
                    will be used
                    within CISBAN to have a shorter (than the LSID), biologist-friendly human-readable name that can be
                    used by the
                    biologist. I didn't use Identifiable.name for this purpose as it is non-unique and I didn't wish to
                    change the
                    purpose of that attribute from the standard. Also, a few more bugs in the FuGE-OM were discovered
                    and fixed.
                    Finally, we've now had two internal live demos which has provided us with a lot of useful feedback
                    both in
                    functionality and in look-and-feel. Work is progressing well.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Status: January 2007">

                <p>
                    The Milestone 3 FuGE-OM has been extended to include a set of classes whose sole purpose is to
                    provide a basis
                    for a versioning system conforming to the
                    <a href="http://lsid.sourceforge.net">LSID specification</a>
                    . XML
                    marshaling and unmarshaling code has been added to and integrated into the FuGE Milestone 3 toolkit
                    available
                    from
                    the
                    <a href="http://fuge.sourceforge.net/dev/index.php">FuGE project development pages</a>
                    . Testing using XML
                    based on the FuGE-ML XSD (created with randomly-generated values) is progressing well. Similarly,
                    the JSP-based
                    front-end is well into development and will be finished in a matter of weeks.
                </p>

                <p>
                    Back to the
                    <a href="index.html">SyMBA home page</a>
                    .
                </p>

            </subsection>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>